Guide to the Thomas Irwin Emerson Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence and Subject Files, 1933-1988; Series I
  - Group libel, 1975, undated (Box 28, Folder 417)
  - Harper, Fowler, 1958-1966 (Box 28, Folder 418 - 420)
  - Harrison v. McNamara, 1962-1965 (Box 28, Folder 421 - 425)
  - House Internal Security Committee
    - General, 1969-1977 (Box 28, Folder 426)
    - Ichord Resolution, 1967-1968, undated (Box 28, Folder 427)
    - Petition to abolish, 1964-1974 (Box 29, Folder 428 - 431)
  - House Un-American Activities Committee
    - General, 1965-1967 (Box 29, Folder 432)
    - Imbrie Committee, 1960 (Box 29, Folder 433)
    - National Committee to Abolish, 1964-1970 (Box 29, Folder 434 - 436)
    - Petition to abolish, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 437 - 438)
    - U.S. v. Yellin, 1960-1963 (Box 29, Folder 439)
  - Intelligence agencies, 1971-1985, undated (Box 30, Folder 440 - 449)
  - Internal security
    - Classification of government information, 1972-1980 (Box 30, Folder 450)
    - FBI charter bill, 1979-1980 (Box 30, Folder 451)
    - Internal Security Act of 1950
      - General, 1948-1963 (Box 31, Folder 452 - 454)
      - Detention provisions, 1970-1971 (Box 31, Folder 455)
      - 1968 amendments, 1967-1968 (Box 31, Folder 456)
      - Registration provisions, 1961-1969, undated (Box 31, Folder 457 - 460)
    - Internal Security Act of 1969 [also known as the Eastland Bill], 1968-1969 (Box 31, Folder 461 - 462)
    - Internal security committees, 1981-1982 (Box 31, Folder 463)
    - Legislation, 1968-1972 (Box 32, Folder 464 - 466)
    - McCarran Act, 1970, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 467)
      See also: box 31, folders 452 - 454
  - International Committee of Comparative Law, 1957 (Box 32, Folder 468)
  - James Madison Constitutional Law Institute, 1969-1972 (Box 32, Folder 469)
  - Jane Bolin Symposium, 1978-1979 (Box 32, Folder 470)
  - Judicial review, Undated (Box 32, Folder 471)
  - Jury [proposed reforms to the grand jury system], 1971-1974 (Box 32, Folder 472)
  - Ku Klux Klan, 1965, 1981-1982, undated (Box 32, Folder 473)
    See also: box 53, folder 756
  - Labor
    - General, 1937 (Box 32, Folder 474)
    - Fair Labor Standards Act, 1945-1946 (Box 32, Folder 475)
    - National Labor Law Center, 1981 (Box 32, Folder 476)
    - National Labor Relations Act
      - General, 1934, 1974, undated (Box 32, Folder 477)
      - Amendments, 1935-1939 (Box 33, Folder 478 - 484)
      - American Federation of Labor amendments, 1939 (Box 33, Folder 485)
      - Court decisions, 1939-1940 (Box 33, Folder 486)
      - Legal memoranda, 1933-1935 (Box 33, Folder 487 - 488)
      - Legislative history, 1934-1935 (Box 34, Folder 489 - 491)
      - Model labor relations act for states, 1937 (Box 34, Folder 492)
      - Norton amendments, 1940 (Box 34, Folder 493)
      - Smith Committee amendments, 1940 (Box 34, Folder 494 - 495)
    - National Labor Relations Board
      - General, 1939-1949, 1960, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 496 - 498)
      - Labor relations, 1935-1938 (Box 34, Folder 499)
      - Litigation, 1934-1935 (Box 34, Folder 500)
      - Press releases, 1937-1938 (Box 34, Folder 501)
      - Smith Committee, 1939-1950 (Box 35, Folder 502 - 506)
      - Southern Steamship Co. argument, 1939-1940 (Box 35, Folder 507)
      - Statistics of operation, 1936-1940 (Box 35, Folder 508 - 510)
      - Textile bill, 1936-1937 (Box 35, Folder 511)
    - National War Labor Board, 1945-1946 (Box 35, Folder 512 - 514)
    - "Subversive" activities in labor, 1955-1959, undated (Box 35, Folder 515)
  - Lavietes, Paul, 1956-1957 (Box 36, Folder 516 - 519)
  - Law enforcement, 1961-1972 (Box 36, Folder 520)
  - Legal assistance, 1964-1965 (Box 36, Folder 521)
  - Legislative committees [witness protection], 1948-1952, 1965-1969, undated (Box 36, Folder 522 - 523)
  - Livingston v. Ullman, 1959, 1962 (Box 36, Folder 524)
  - Local 34, Federation of University Employees, 1983-1985 (Box 36, Folder 525 - 526)
  - Lockerty v. Phillips, 1942-1943 (Box 36, Folder 527)
  - Loyalty programs
    See also: box 28, folders 421 - 425
    See also: box 64, folders 885 - 889
    - General, 1947-1950, 1965-1968 (Box 37, Folder 528 - 530)
    - Attorney General's list, Undated (Box 37, Folder 531)
    - Blitz Amendment, 1981-1982 (Box 37, Folder 532)
    - Executive documents, 1948-1949, 1970 (Box 37, Folder 533 - 534)
    - Federal loyalty program, 1954-1969, 1984-1985 (Box 37, Folder 535 - 536)
    - Industry, 1967, undated (Box 37, Folder 537)
    - Legal memoranda, cases, 1950-1951, undated (Box 37, Folder 538 - 539)
    - Legislation, 1972 (Box 37, Folder 540)
    - Legislative documents, 1947-1965 (Box 37, Folder 541)
    - "Loyalty Among Government Employees" [correspondence and notes regarding article], 1949-1950, undated (Box 37, Folder 542 - 544)
    - Loyalty program for lawyers, 1950-1957, 1966-1971 (Box 38, Folder 545 - 547)
    - Mail delivery, 1959-1965, undated (Box 38, Folder 548)
    - Military forces, Undated (Box 38, Folder 549)
    - Procedure for enforcement of loyalty program, 1962, undated (Box 38, Folder 550)
    - Proposals for change, 1953-1959 (Box 38, Folder 551)
    - Rein, David, 1940-1948, undated (Box 38, Folder 552)
    - State and local, 1951-1952, 1965, undated (Box 38, Folder 553)
    - Statements, articles, etc., 1947-1955 (Box 38, Folder 554 - 555)
    - Transcripts of hearings, 1947-1948 (Box 38, Folder 556)
  - Maintaining the peace [police intervention during public assemblies], 1973, undated (Box 38, Folder 557)
  - May Day, 1970 [Black Panther rally in New Haven, Connecticut], 1969-1970 (Box 38, Folder 558)
  - Media [proposed postal rate increase, notes for speech entitled "A Responsible Press in a Free Society"], 1972-1982 (Box 38, Folder 559)
  - Media Access Project, 1976-1986 (Box 39, Folder 560)
  - Meiklejohn Civil Liberties Institute, 1983-1985 (Box 39, Folder 561)
  - Military
    - Draft, 1980 (Box 39, Folder 562)
    - Freedom of expression, 1961-1971, undated (Box 39, Folder 563)
      See also: box 11, folder 159
    - Individual rights, 1971, undated (Box 39, Folder 564)
    - Mitchell, David case [selective service], 1965-1967 (Box 39, Folder 565 - 566)
    - Selective service, 1966-1969 (Box 39, Folder 567)
    - Wartime draft opposition, 1966-1968 (Box 39, Folder 568)
  - Mory's case, 1971-1975 (Box 39, Folder 569)
  - Mundt Bill, 1948-1950 (Box 39, Folder 570 - 571)
  - National Assembly on Teaching the Principles of the Bill of Rights, 1963-1965 (Box 39, Folder 572 - 575)
  - National Committee Against Repressive Legislation
    - General, 1970-1985 (Box 40, Folder 576 - 585)
    - Bolling Committee testimony, 1973-1974 (Box 40, Folder 586)
    - First Amendment Foundation of Southern California, 1983-1985 (Box 40, Folder 587 - 588)
    - NCARL v. FBI, 1983-1984 (Box 41, Folder 589)
  - National Committee to Repeal the McCarran Act, 1952-1965 (Box 41, Folder 590)
  - National Council of the Arts, Sciences and Professions, 1947-1955 (Box 41, Folder 591 - 593)
  - National Labor Relations Act
    See: box 32, folder 477
    See: box 33, folders 478 - 484
    See: box 34, folders 489 - 491
  - National Labor Relations Board
    See: box 34, folders 496 - 498
    See: box 35, folders 502 - 506
  - National Lawyers Guild, 1976-1984 (Box 41, Folder 594 - 599)
  - National security, 1960-1985, undated (Box 42, Folder 600 - 604)
  - New Haven Civil Liberties Council, 1940-1971 (Box 42, Folder 605 - 611)
  - New Haven wiretap suit ( Abramovitz v. Ahern ), 1978-1985 (Box 42, Folder 612 - 613)
  - New left, Undated (Box 43, Folder 614)
  - Office of Economic Stabilization, 1945 (Box 43, Folder 615)
  - Office of Price Administration
    - General, 1941-1943 (Box 43, Folder 616 - 618)
    - Bibb Manufacturing Co. argument, 1943 (Box 43, Folder 619)
    - Correspondence, memoranda, 1941-1947, undated (Box 43, Folder 620 - 621)
    - Emergency court of appeals, Undated (Box 43, Folder 622)
    - Enforcement
      - General, 1944-1945 (Box 43, Folder 623)
      - History, Undated (Box 43, Folder 624 - 625)
      - Investigation manual, 1944 (Box 44, Folder 626)
      - Litigation, 1942-1947 (Box 44, Folder 627 - 628)
      - New York, 1945 (Box 44, Folder 629)
      - Organization, 1943-1945 (Box 44, Folder 630)
      - Policy, 1943-1944 (Box 44, Folder 631)
      - Reports, 1944 (Box 44, Folder 632)
      - Statistics, 1944 (Box 44, Folder 633 - 634)
      - Weekly letters to field, 1944-1945 (Box 44, Folder 635)
    - Executive order, 1941 (Box 44, Folder 636)
  - Office of War Mobilization and Reconversion, 1945-1946 (Box 45, Folder 637 - 648)
  - Origins of the American Corporate State, 1972-1974 (Box 45, Folder 649)
  - Peace
    See also: box 56, folders 790 - 798
    - Disarmament, 1961-1965 (Box 45, Folder 650)
    - International relations, 1947-1965 (Box 45, Folder 651 - 652)
    - Universities Committee on the Problem of War and Peace, 1963-1965 (Box 45, Folder 653)
  - Peoples Party of Connecticut
    See: box 53, folders 757 - 759
    See: box 54, folders 760 - 766
    See: box 55, folders 773 - 775
    See: box 56, folder 787
  - Permanent Commission on the Status of Women
    - General
      - 1975-1976 (Box 46, Folder 654 - 663)
      - 1976-1979 (Box 47, Folder 664 - 671)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 47, Folder 672 - 674)
      - 1981-1985 (Box 48, Folder 675 - 676)
    - Family Law Subcommittee, 1977-1979 (Box 48, Folder 677 - 679)
    - Legislative Committee
      - 1975-1977 (Box 48, Folder 680 - 684)
      - 1977-1986 (Box 49, Folder 685 - 694)
  - Personal security, 1948-1964, undated (Box 49, Folder 695 - 698)
  - Phi Alpha Delta bicentennial partnership program, 1982-1983 (Box 50, Folder 699)
  - Planned Parenthood of Connecticut, 1961, 1978-1985 (Box 50, Folder 700 - 702)
  - Poe v. Ullman, 1958-1960 (Box 50, Folder 703)
  - Police brutality, 1951-1955 (Box 50, Folder 704)
  - Police review boards, 1964-1971 (Box 50, Folder 705)
  - Political and civil rights
    See also: box 14, folder 217
    - General, 1948-1959, 1976-1982 (Box 50, Folder 706)
    - Aged, 1976-1978 (Box 50, Folder 707)
    - Aliens (immigrants), 1947-1985, undated (Box 50, Folder 708 - 711)
    - Bill of Rights conference, 1949-1963 (Box 50, Folder 712 - 713)
    - Children, 1973-1978 (Box 50, Folder 714)
      See also: box 32, folder 470
    - Corporations, 1974-1979 (Box 51, Folder 715)
    - Federal jurisdiction, 1976-1977 (Box 51, Folder 716)
    - Government employees, 1949, 1968, undated (Box 51, Folder 717)
    - Handicapped, 1983 (Box 51, Folder 718)
    - Homosexuals, 1975-1983 (Box 51, Folder 719)
    - International, 1948-1980, undated (Box 51, Folder 720 - 722)
    - Labor, 1949 (Box 51, Folder 723)
    - Mentally ill, 1979 (Box 51, Folder 724)
    - Procedure, 1949, 1976, undated (Box 51, Folder 725)
    - Protection from government, 1947-1953, 1970-1971, undated (Box 51, Folder 726 - 727)
    - Protection from individuals, 1947-1952, undated (Box 51, Folder 728)
    - Right of franchise, 1947-1964 (Box 51, Folder 729 - 731)
    - Smith Act, 1952-1962, undated (Box 51, Folder 732)
  - Political organizations and expression
    - General, 1949-1967 (Box 51, Folder 733)
    - Federal registration laws, 1983 (Box 51, Folder 734)
    - Nature of the Communist threat, 1947-1956, undated (Box 51, Folder 735)
      See also: box 16, folder 238
      See also: box 26, folder 380
      See also: box 39, 570 - 571
    - Non-governmental anti-subversive measures, Undated (Box 51, Folder 736)
      See also: box 37, folder 537
    - State and local anti-subversive laws, 1947-1957 (Box 52, Folder 737)
    - State legislative committees, 1959-1965 (Box 52, Folder 738)
  - Population Institute, 1981-1984 (Box 52, Folder 739)
  - Pornography, 1983-1985 (Box 52, Folder 740 - 741)
  - President
    - Executive privilege, 1971-1973, undated (Box 52, Folder 742)
    - Impeachment, 1973-1977, undated (Box 52, Folder 743 - 744)
    - Office and powers, 1952-1976, undated (Box 52, Folder 745 - 746)
  - President's Committee on Civil Rights, 1947-1948 (Box 52, Folder 747)
  - Prisoner's rights, 1973, 1978 (Box 52, Folder 748)
  - Privacy, 1966-1981, undated (Box 53, Folder 749 - 754)
  - Privacy and freedom of the press [paper and article], 1978-1979, undated (Box 53, Folder 755)
  - Progressive Alliance -Task Force on Lawlessness and Violence Against Minorities, 1980-1981 (Box 53, Folder 756)
  - Progressive Party
    - General
      - 1947-1948 (Box 53, Folder 757 - 759)
      - 1949-1953 (Box 54, Folder 760 - 766)
    - Conventions, 1948-1949 (Box 54, Folder 767 - 769)
    - International, 1947-1950 (Box 54, Folder 770 - 771)
    - Materials for speeches, 1948 (Box 54, Folder 772)
    - National Committee and Executive Committee, 1948-1950 (Box 55, Folder 773 - 775)
    - New England Committee on a Progressive Program, 1949 (Box 55, Folder 776)
    - Political action committee, 1946-1948 (Box 55, Folder 777)
    - Progressive Citizens of America, 1946-1948 (Box 55, Folder 778 - 784)
    - Speeches, 1947-1949 (Box 55, Folder 785 - 786)
    - State Executive Committee, 1948-1950 (Box 56, Folder 787)
    - Wallace for President Committee, 1948 (Box 56, Folder 788)
  - Project to Return Inmates to Schools, Occupations and Neighborhoods, 1974 (Box 56, Folder 789)
  - Promoting Enduring Peace, 1951-1986 (Box 56, Folder 790 - 798)
  - Race relations, 1949-1961, 1970, 1972 (Box 57, Folder 799 - 800)
  - Racism and the First Amendment, 1973-1981, undated (Box 57, Folder 801)
  - Radio and television [controls on programing, children's advertising regulations], 1959-1983 (Box 57, Folder 802 - 803)
  - Reapportionment [government representation based on population], 1962-1973 (Box 57, Folder 804 - 806)
    See also: box 85, folders 41 - 49
  - Rehnquist and Powell Supreme Court nominations, 1971-1972 (Box 57, Folder 807)
  - Reilly, William R. case, 1975-1978 (Box 57, Folder 808)
  - Republican Party v. Tashjian, 1984 (Box 57, Folder 809)
  - Right of advocacy, 1950-1978 (Box 57, Folder 810 - 811)
  - Right of anonymity, 1958-1966, undated (Box 58, Folder 812)
  - Right of association, 1950-1970, undated (Box 58, Folder 813 - 815)
  - Right of franchise, 1966-1973, undated (Box 58, Folder 816)
  - Rights of employees of non-governmental organizations, 1978-1983 (Box 58, Folder 817)
  - Rights of government employees, 1967-1978, undated (Box 58, Folder 818 - 819)
  - Right-wing movements, 1962-1965 (Box 58, Folder 820)
  - Searches and seizures, 1963-1974 (Box 58, Folder 821)
  - Secrecy agreements, 1983-1984 (Box 58, Folder 822)
  - Self-incrimination, 1953, 1960, undated (Box 58, Folder 823 - 824)
  - Sobell, Morton case
    See also: box 24, 353 - 355
    See also: box 61, 850 - 853
    - General, 1952-1963 (Box 58, Folder 825 - 826)
    - Clippings, 1956-1969 (Box 58, Folder 827 - 828)
    - Committee to Secure Justice for Morton Sobell, 1955-1969 (Box 59, Folder 829 - 831)
    - Correspondence, 1955-1970 (Box 59, Folder 832 - 835)
    - Letters in favor of release, 1961-1964 (Box 59, Folder 836 - 837)
    - Legal documents, 1956-1969 (Box 60, Folder 838 - 846)
    - Meetings, 1959-1960 (Box 60, Folder 847)
    - Notes for briefs and arguments, 1967-1969, undated (Box 61, Folder 848)
    - Publications, 1953-1958 (Box 61, Folder 849)
  - Sobell-Rosenberg case, 1951-1953, 1972-1977 (Box 61, Folder 850 - 853)
  - Social legislation, 1957-1958, undated (Box 61, Folder 854 - 855)
  - Social Security, 1945-1958, 1981 (Box 61, Folder 856 - 859)
  - Society of American Law Teachers, 1972-1985 (Box 62, Folder 860 - 871)
  - Southern New England Telephone (SNET) case, 1972-1978, undated (Box 63, Folder 872 - 873)
  - "The Speaker... A Film about Freedom", 1978-1979 (Box 63, Folder 874)
  - State and local anti-subversive laws, 1964, undated (Box 63, Folder 875)
  - State of Connecticut v. Griswold and Buxton, 1947, 1961-1964 (Box 63, Folder 876 - 877)
  - Steuart argument, 1943-1944 (Box 63, Folder 878)
  - Subcommittee on Constitutional Rights of the Committee on the Judiciary, 1955 (Box 63, Folder 879)
  - Supreme Court, 1937, 1963-1980 (Box 63, Folder 880 - 881)
  - Surveillance, 1970-1971, undated (Box 63, Folder 882)
  - Sweatt v. Painter, et al., 1948-1950 (Box 64, Folder 883 - 884)
  - Sweezy v. New Hampshire, 1954-1958 (Box 64, Folder 885 - 889)
  - Teaching the Bill of Rights [high school curriculum project], 1963-1967 (Box 64, Folder 890 - 892)
  - Terrorism, 1977-1984 (Box 65, Folder 893)
  - Treason, 1955-1963, undated (Box 65, Folder 894)
  - Trubek v. Ullman, 1959-1961 (Box 65, Folder 895)
  - United States Labor Party, 1975-1976 (Box 65, Folder 896)
  - United States v. The Boston Globe, 1971 (Box 65, Folder 897)
  - United States v. Flynn, et al., 1951-1954 (Box 65, Folder 898 - 905)
  - United States v. The New York Times Company, 1970-1977, undated (Box 66, Folder 906 - 910)
  - United States v. Silverman
    - Appeals, clear and present danger, factual materials, factual proof of clear and present danger, 1952-1956, undated (Box 66, Folder 911 - 919)
    - General, indictments, motions, 1954-1958 (Box 67, Folder 920 - 922)
  - United States v. The Washington Post, 1971 (Box 67, Folder 923)
  - Vietnam War, 1963-1973, undated (Box 67, Folder 924 - 927)
  - Voting Rights Act of 1965, 1960-1965, undated (Box 67, Folder 928)
  - Voting Rights Act of 1982, 1981 (Box 67, Folder 929)
  - Willard v. Ullman, 1959 (Box 67, Folder 930)
  - Wiretapping, 1952-1972, undated (Box 67, Folder 931 - 932)
    See also: Series I. Correspondence and Subject Files, 1933-1988 Folder 612 - 613
  - Women's Law Project, 1974-1984 (Box 67, Folder 933 - 934)
  - Women's rights, 1971-1988 (Box 68, Folder 935 - 940)
  - Yale Law Journal, 1955-1975 (Box 68, Folder 941)
  - Yale Law Journal Board of Directors, 1976 (Box 68, Folder 942)
  - Yale Law School
    - General, 1960-1971 (Box 68, Folder 943)
    - Black Law Students Union, 1969-1971 (Box 68, Folder 944)
    - Committee on long range educational policy planning, 1962-1968 (Box 68, Folder 945 - 947)
    - Committee on placement, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 948)
    - Curriculum committee
      - 1947-1949 (Box 68, Folder 949 - 950)
      - 1950-1968 (Box 69, Folder 951 - 962)
      - 1969-1971 (Box 70, Folder 963 - 970)
    - Faculty meetings, 1957-1970 (Box 70, Folder 971 - 973)
    - Faculty papers [correspondence and memoranda]
      - 1947-1955 (Box 70, Folder 974 - 975)
      - 1956-1964 (Box 71, Folder 976 - 988)
      - 1965-1970 (Box 72, Folder 989 - 1001)
    - Racial matters committee, 1969 (Box 73, Folder 1002)
    - Student representation committee, 1968-1969 (Box 73, Folder 1003)
  - Yale Legislative Services, 1969-1970 (Box 73, Folder 1004 - 1006)
- Personal Papers, 1937-1987; Series II
  The series includes correspondence and printed material that provide general information about Thomas Emerson. The Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) records Emerson received as a result of a Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) request highlight the series. The FBI records, consisting largely of reports and memoranda, document the bureau's surveillance of Emerson as a suspected member of the Communist Party. The transcript from an FBI agent's interview of Emerson in volume II is the most poignant documentation of the scope of the investigation and its effect on Emerson. The FBI files are arranged in two runs, apparently the result of two distinct FOIA requests. Emerson divided the first run into volumes arranged chronologically. The second run is not divided into volumes and is arranged in only loose chronological order. Much of the second run appears to duplicate the first.
  The material under the heading of loyalty investigations provides further evidence of Emerson defending himself against accusations made by the FBI and includes written statements by himself and others denying those charges. The series also includes biographical information and documentation of Emerson's sabbaticals.
  - Admission to bar, 1965 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Applications and appointments, 1937-1976 (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Awards, 1983-1985 (Box 74, Folder 3 - 4)
  - Biographical information, 1963, undated (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - China [potential visit to lecture], 1979, undated (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Conferences, 1973-1985 (Box 74, Folder 7 - 12)
  - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) request
    - Central Intelligence Agency, 1943-1977 (Box 74, Folder 13)
    - Civil Service Commission, 1941-1947, 1977 (Box 74, Folder 14)
    - Department of State, 1977, undated (Box 74, Folder 15)
    - Department of the Treasury, 1941-1942, 1977 (Box 74, Folder 16)
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation file
      - Volume I [investigation of Emerson when he was being considered for a position in the Department of Justice], 1941 (Box 75, Folder 17 - 19)
      - Volume II [investigation of Emerson under the Hatch Act; investigation of Emerson by the Treasury Intelligence Service for employment at the Office of Price Administration; Emerson interviewed by the FBI], 1941-1947 (Box 75, Folder 20 - 22)
      - Volume III [memoranda regarding Emerson's Yale Law Journal article on the loyalty program; placement of Emerson on the security index; copies of pages from Emerson's address book], 1948-1950 (Box 75, Folder 23 - 26)
      - Volume IV [New Haven FBI office reports; copies of newspaper articles], 1951-1952 (Box 75, Folder 27 - 28)
      - Volume V [reports on Emerson's trip to Europe; photocopy of article about Emerson in Yale Law Report ], 1953-1957 (Box 75, Folder 29 - 31)
      - Volume VI [reports regarding the publication of the second edition of Political and Civil Rights in the United States and Emerson's other activities], 1958-1962 (Box 76, Folder 32 - 34)
      - Volume VII [reports including requests that Emerson be placed on section A of the security index], 1964-1966 (Box 76, Folder 35 - 36)
      - Volume VIII [reports including inquiry from White House, 9/12/68], 1967-1975 (Box 76, Folder 37 - 38)
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation file, version 2
      - 1941-1951 (Box 76, Folder 39 - 45)
      - 1951-1975 [bulk 1953-1966] (Box 77, Folder 46 - 57)
      - 1952-1975 [bulk 1960-1970] (Box 78, Folder 58 - 66)
    - Immigration and Naturalization Service, 1954, 1977 (Box 78, Folder 67)
    - Interstate Commerce Commission, 1967, 1977 (Box 78, Folder 68)
    - Miscellaneous [FBI material, correspondence regarding FOIA request], 1949-1952, 1971-1982 (Box 78, Folder 69 - 71)
    - Naval Intelligence Service, 1959, 1977 (Box 78, Folder 72)
    - Yale University, 1945, 1951 (Box 78, Folder 73)
  - Kinoshita, Tsuyoshi [visiting scholar], 1981-1987, undated (Box 78, Folder 74)
  - Loyalty investigations, 1940-1974 (Box 79, Folder 75 - 82)
  - Passport application [includes photographs], 1952- 1953, undated (Box 79, Folder 83)
  - Petitions, committees, etc., 1961-1978 (Box 79, Folder 84 - 86)
  - Resignation from the Office of Price Administration, 1945 (Box 79, Folder 87)
  - Sabbatical years
    - 1953-1954, England, 1951-1963 (Box 80, Folder 88 - 95)
    - 1960-1961, Washington, D.C., 1959-1963 (Box 80, Folder 96)
    - 1967-1968, Washington, D.C., 1963-1970 (Box 80, Folder 97)
    - 1974-1975, China (Box 80, Folder 98)
    - 1974-1975, Japan
      - American law, Japanese law, 1974-1980 (Box 80, Folder 99 - 100)
      - General, 1972-1981 (Box 81, Folder 101 - 103)
  - Travel
    - England, 1980-1983 (Box 81, Folder 104)
    - Italy and Greece, 1977-1984 (Box 81, Folder 105)
- Writings, 1947-1987; Series III